co-working or co- lurking yeah that's a
word I said on accident while I was
talking about this with my twitch stream
hey twitch say hi to YouTube let's talk
about what co-working is what co-
lurking is and why you may or may not
want to do it and I'll try to be brief
um we've had a lot of conversation about
whether it's a good idea or not and
there's been a lot of really great ideas
on both sides um and I'm going to tell
you what my conclusion is and what works
for me and what I've concluded after
actually debating with myself about this
very topic so first of all what is it so
we're going to talk about what it is and
then why you might want to do it or why
you might not want to do it all right
and how with so co-working is the idea
of of grabbing your copy and going to
work with somebody else who doesn't work
and your same place of employment that's
it that's all it is co-working just
means that you're working next to them
you're collocating and you're working
right next to them and that's that's
that's really it right um it can be that
you get up and you drive to some place
that you rent and you you sit in a
co-working space that's been you know
made to to really be happy it looks like
Silicon Valley or something it could be
you go to Panera Bread you could go to
Taco Bell it doesn't matter you just
want to be around other people while
you're working um for full disclosure at
one point I had a guy who was
self-employed very very successfully by
the way over 200,000 a year easily doing
computer engineering on his own time
doing and he would he had nobody around
to work with so he and I became
accountability partners and we would go
to coffee shops and sit next to each
other and he would get his work done and
I would get my work done and it worked
it worked for a while um but it you know
it was there was always a logistics of
getting together and all that thing so
you but that is one example of Co of
co-working another example of co-working
is something I call co- lurking as I
call that that on accident where you go
to a twitch stream or a YouTube stream
or or to a YouTube channel where they're
playing you know chill up music and you
just sit there and you put that on the
on the on the screen on the side and you
do your thing A lot of people do this a
lot of people love to do this and I'm
not really against it but I've decided
not to do it um I did it for a long time
I did it I put asky fish up and I put
the music up and then I had it there's a
place to go in and chat anytime you
wanted to and it was kind of nice that
feeling of like hey my community my
friends in my community most of my
friends I'm happy to report are actually
people that I met through live streaming
um I got my current jobs for live
streaming I met my current wife online
you know it's it's not a bad thing and
do I meet people in real life yes but
the point is is that is that um hey how
are you
so people who are in the room with you
so to speak make you feel more
comfortable and cozy and I totally get
it I totally get it but here's the real
question are you more productive by
having that Community always available
to go look at right and and are you so
addicted to dopamine um that you need to
you know go go look at it so that brings
the next question up so now that we know
what co-working is whether you're paying
you know 200 bucks a month for a Wei
work space uh or you know you're you're
just doing it online and you're just co-
lorking through twitch we know what it
is but is it effective and this is the
part where I hate to admit to myself
sometimes um the truth yeah lazy
slacker has just subscribed um I
honestly do not think that either
co-working or coworking improves
people's
efficiency um and for that reason I am
no longer going to do it even when it's
from the beach or the seventh floor of a
of a Marriot Hotel in sparenberg and you
got a great view I'm not going to do it
anymore because I happen to think that
it does distract from people's
productivity uh not to mention the fact
that it it really pre on people's foma
and I actually kind of you know foma I
actually kind of joked about that right
it's like you know I have people in my
chat that I deeply respect who say
things like oh I miss Rob when I'm not
online for a bit and and I appreciate it
I really do I I also miss you that's one
of the reasons that I end up streaming
uh when I'm sitting in the chair over
here uh or not even on the screen
sometimes and I'm like coding away
tapping out something that you guys will
never know um or even on a conference
call sometimes I've been streaming that
because it's nice to have in fact I've
even commented on the comments on the
conference call in my chat while it was
happening um you know rather than let my
brain go to a place that is more
productive which reminds me I brought
this topic up to my wife Doris who's
very creative and very successful and
you know she's a Project Director um you
know for an art residency program and
many other things and she she said uh
she says yeah but it's that boredom that
Sparks creativity that's paraphrasing
her I think she said boredom is the
spark of creativity and she said and
that got me really thinking hard she
said let me so she said because yeah but
it's it's that boredom it's that
uncomfortable place when you're just
with yourself and your work that's where
creativity happens and that really blew
my mind I mean God you know I was like
really Blown Away by that thought
because when then I started you know
re-evaluating every moment that I've
ever you know been coding or something
and I I put my earplugs in cuz I'm
really OCD about the or about you know
whatever the keyboard noise and things
like that I don't like it and that you
know it's that moment when you're just
staring at the canvas or you're staring
at your computer screen or you're going
back and forth with the keys and like I
do I I fidget with my keyboard because I
don't know what to type but I want to
type something it's that moment where
you're forced your brain is forced to to
focus on the task at hand and and get
creative and think about different
things and that that applies for a
conference call as well that boring
conference call that you think is not
related to anything yeah there might be
something said in the conference call
that Sparks a you know a little bit of
creativity and boredom but maybe
triggers another idea in fact when I was
in the gifted and talented program when
I was learning you know things at Junior
High I
remember that uh Mr lanquist who was my
teacher he used to say there's no such
thing is a bad idea during the creative
process because and we want to refrain
from judging creative ideas even if
they're silly because they can spark the
you know a more sane approach to it and
maybe get the thought process going in a
direction that is more realistic so this
is why we do not ear we do not critique
bad ideas early in the creative process
because we want to let them flow and
come out because that's going to end up
triggering better ideas later and you're
eventually going to it might you know it
might be five tangents away from an
actual good idea but it's that boredom
it's that focus and you know this Zen
idea of being present um you know it's
there's like longstanding historical
evidence um that being present is more
valuable use of your time whether you're
you know drinking coffee or with your
which you know if I was being pres I
wouldn't be talking while I was drinking
my coffee right I would just be drinking
my coffee and beholding the coffee and
like being totally into my coffee that
you know a lot of Zen you know Buddhists
would or meditation Specialists would
tell you that's the way to be about
everything that means if you're going to
go to the beach you you know you focus
on the bikinies and the and the ocean
and the sand you don't try to bring your
computer there and code at the same
time because then you won't enjoy either
of them you you'll end up producing
horrible code you'll ruin your computer
because you have sand in it and you also
miss the best bikinis and and and waves
those sweet
waves so be present right so so this is
the reason that I personally think um I
think I think that co-working and co-
lurking they they feed into two very
very real needs that we have the need to
to not be alone to have people around us
and the the need to feel like we're
getting stuff done well we're really not
Stephen arov made a book called uh the
compass in the square and and many other
books about time management and whatever
you think of Stephen arov I really like
the quadrant in it's the the the the
quadrant the the conjoin triangles no
it's this a reference to Silicon Valley
joke um but there's like you know just a
it's a box and there's like four
quadrants in it and I think it's
quadrant three which is you know it's
like urgent and important right and um
and that particular quadrant the not
urgent and not important I think is
where you know random chat with with
people in a in a colorking space or you
know or like you know you know looking
over your screen at the person and the
Panera Bread and making a you know
thinking about what is that on their
t-shirt you know those kinds of things
those
distractions that that occupy our our
mental space um Can detract they can
detract from our ability to produce but
they feel sometimes they feel good it's
like it's like how come you know like a
a live stream or something like this
feels like you're getting stuff done
when you should maybe be doing something
else now
to be
fair
bikini um so I you know I I I do think
and I I'm going to do these coffee you
know talk kind of streams pretty
regularly but the the focus is on
co-working this if focusing on
interacting with my twitch stream and
coming up with conclusions and making a
a very hopefully focused video about our
conclusions is more in line with you
know focus and and meditation and you
know staying on point than it is for me
to just you know um Let The Stream Run
for six hours with good music in the
background and maybe we have random chat
about thing um so I'm gonna say that
it's probably better to get to deal with
that loneliness and to dive into the
work that needs to be done and focus on
getting that work done and time boxing
which I made another video about whether
you use Pomodoro method or some other
method 45 minutes is way too little for
most of the coding that I do it's more
like 3 hours then then you can come up
for air and when you come up for air
come up for air come go check out a
stream like this copy talk stream or any
other where where you can just talk and
you can interact and you can like really
really have a water cooler experience
you know and and and get some more
motivation and maybe share your ideas
and stuff like that and then go back in
and go do it but that that doesn't
happen if if you're you've got you know
the con distraction around you in fact a
lot of people who several people
suggested that going to Panera Bread or
something like that is actually
impossible for them because they there's
just too much activity there's too much
distraction and that it really depends
on you actually some of the best code
I've ever gotten done touch grass yes go
outdoors and and everybody knows that
I'm that guy right I I I want to work
hard and then I want to go play hard
outside but but when you see other other
things going on sometimes people concate
some seriously some of the best code
I've ever done was when the white noise
was so intense it was in a pub I would
put my I would um go to the the pub and
I would bring my earplug in case I
needed them I'd order a pint and then I
would put my laptop up and then there
was like live music and there was just
tons and tons of white noise and in fact
there was so much noise that I was
actually really able to focus on the
code and so I was the weird guy in the
corner in the couch you know writing
code with all of this stuff going around
was I a Ive I felt effective I don't
know I I did write some of my best code
during those times because it just I
don't know why it just was the energy of
the place and everything um but at that
point I would argue that there was so
much distraction that that just it just
became one huge wall of white noise and
and sometimes I need white noise to not
it was either that or the Balmer Peak
from the Pint I was drinking I don't
know there's a separate video on the
Balmer
Peak so co-working co-working is is not
something that I am going to do or
encourage people to do I if if you want
to do it and you find Value in it please
let me know please you know write a
comment in the YouTube here or um you
know just just come on in but but but
the the takeaway from this is that I I
am not going to be doing co-working
streams anymore I will be
doing like streams where I'm trying to
figure something out and I'm talking
through it interactively with the chat
um and you're welcome to come into those
if you have time and you're you know
your day is is okay to be distracted
with that if that's something you're
okay with but I am not going to do the
you know the DJ music so and it's sad
because I really love being a DJ I do so
maybe we'll have to have focused DJ
streams where I pick the music that we
listen to and we can talk about it and
we can jam out and have some fun and
maybe I can make a very dedicated DJ
stream instead of having this big long
drawn out co-working stream right if I
do a DJ stream by the way I'm going to
be dancing and stuff because that's
usually what I
do so that's all maybe rethink your
dedication to co-working and co-working
maybe focus more let yourself be bored
and let that boredom turn into
creativity and then after you've created
something awesome and you've delivered
on it go have fun go touch grass go come
hang out with us and we'll be here